本作品由 NORM TEAM 荣誉出品
下载后仅供学习交流,严禁用于商业途径
更多精彩 尽在 www.normteam.com
压制: mzj5212  字幕:mzj5212
请告诉机主，我不大舒服
Tell her I'm not feeling well.
我很想看医生
I want to see a doctor.
还有，我很想见她
And I want to see her.
那请问你贵姓呢？
Your name, sir?
我叫阿杰
I'm Kit!
但机主说不接受你留言
But she said
she won't take your messages.
谢谢
Thanks!
真的是你？
It's really you!
你这么迟？
You're late.
你怎么搞的，打扮成这样？
Why are you dressed like this?
人家今晚拼了老命呀
She's going for broke tonight.
Johnny呢？
Where's Johnny?
他有份工作要赶，所以先回去影楼去
He's busy at the studio.
这样子
Okay!
不是吧，圣诞节还要“干”？
Busy? On Christmas Day?
你穿成这样，到底想怎样？
Why are you dressed like this?
想吃豆腐，行不行？
I'm dressed for sex. Problem?
弄了个新玩意，看
Another new one? Look!
你的手好冷
Your hands are cold.
掉不掉色？
Will the color fade?
都被你擦掉了
You just rubbed it off.
Johnny送你来的？
Did Johnny drop you off?
当然不是，我自己坐车来的
Of course not. I took a taxi.
他干完事来不来？
Will he come when he's done?
还是“干”完其他事才来呢？
Or will he come before he comes?
他做完事后要打电话给我
He'll call me when he's done.
最便宜是你吧，拣圣诞节生日
Lucky you, born on Christmas Day.
谢谢
Thanks!
她没份出钱的
She didn't contribute.
早料到了
I didn't think so.
求求你，正正经经找份工作吧
Please find a real job.
看你，这种东西真能混饭吃吗
Can you make a living on this?
就是，你至少要找个男朋友
At least find a boy friend.
现在孤苦伶仃，无依无靠
You're so lonely.
你们好老套
And you're a nag.
我先去撒泡尿
I'm going to pee.
批准你去
Here's a bottle.
你知不知道她刚才说我什么？
You know what she told me?
什么？
What?
她说我要一辈子打工
I'll be celibate,
还有一辈子没男人碰
and work like a mule all my life.
多么大的打击
What a blow.
就是
I know!
哪样打击较大呢？
Which is worse?
什么？
What's up?
你太离谱，说我没男人碰
You're mean, saying I'll be celibate.
不好吗？
That's bad?
当然不好，去你的乌鸦嘴
Of course! Curse your mouth!
我帮你算命，当做生日礼物
My birthday gift to you is,
I'll tell your fortune.
不要
No!
千万别上当  关你什么事？
- Don't!
- Mind your own business.
你们运程不大好
You're not good together.
这张牌代表谎言
This card means "Lies".
即是说不是他骗你就你骗他
One of you lies to the other.
最后一张牌原是最好的一张
The last card is the best.
但是你太倒霉，牌调转过来
But it's upside-down.
即是没了
Which cancels it.
看来，没有好下场
You guys are doomed.
没有了？
That's it?
那能不能查到…
Can you check to see...
是我骗他，还是他骗我？
Who lies to whom?
你好，生日快乐
Hi! Happy Birthday!
谢谢
Thank you!
你们见过面了？Alan，Jeannie
You've met? Alan, meet Jeannie.
见过一次面了
We've met once.
Johnny呢？
Where's Johnny?
怎么了？
What's up?
什么事？
What is it?
没什么,刚才Sanni给她和Johnny算命
Sanni predicted their relationship.
说是互相欺骗，没有好下场
And said they'll lie to each other.
不好意思,请问是不是你们订的生日旦糕
Did you order the birthday cake?
怎么搞的？你都说出来了
How can you announce it like that?
对不起
Sorry!
一点惊喜都没了
You ruined the surprise.
怎么回事？走吧？
What?
其实，你别一听她的话就阵脚大乱
Don't believe everything she says.
这些江湖术士
Maybe she's a charlatan.
不收钱，法力可能不灵的
Especially since it was free.
好暴力
So violent.
其实我见过Johnny和一个洋妞在一起
I saw Johnny with a Caucasian Woman.
不是吧？什么时候？
Really? When?
上个星期我开车经过戏院
I drove by the cinema last week.
见到他们看午夜场
Before the midnight show.
有没有拖手？
Were they holding hands?
有吧
I think so!
那个洋妞你认识吗？
Do you know her?
你怎么不早说呢？
Why didn't you tell us?
我怎知道他们现在怎样？
How would I know?
你很灵
You're good!
其实我上星期在影楼见过她
I saw her at the studio.
她是上一辑照片的模特儿
She was the model for his last job.
标不标致？
Is she pretty?
要不现在打电话去影楼盘问他
Call him at the studio.
不用，我打了，没人听
I did. No answer.
说不定和洋妞出去了，没空听
He may be out with her.
真过分
Idiots!
他们把生日旦糕切成十二份
They cut up our cake.
还送给其他客人
And served it to other customers.
问我赔多少钱？赔他的命
They're offering to pay for the cake.
But it won't help.
怎么？
What?
你送Jeannie回去吧
Take Jeannie home.
用不著，我送可以了
No need, I'll do it.
不行，你住元朗那么远
No, you live far away.
最糟的是Sue早走了，她有车
Too bad Sue is gone, she's got a car.
那你呢？
And you?
我等会儿还有约会
I'm going somewhere else.
原来想甩掉男朋友
Trying to get rid of your boyfriend?
我们不要帮她
Let's get going.
Clara叫我送你回去
Clara wants me to take you home.
怎么了？
What?
没事
Nothing!
你没见过Johnny吧？
You never met Johnny?
怎么搞的？那么晚？
Why are you so late?
我加班，吃了东西没有？
Overtime. Did you eat?
还没吃
Not yet!
刚才给你电话怎么没人听？
You didn't answer your phone.
电话坏了
It broke.
坏了，几时坏的？
It did? When?
刚刚
Just now!
刚才喝酒，喝得怎样？
How was drinks?
马马虎虎
Okay!
什么？
What?
马马虎虎
Okay!
马马…
Okay...
这个好吃点
This tastes better.
是吗？
Really?
怎么？还想去哪里？还是回家
Where should we go? Home?
怎么？
What?
你见不到外面站著一个人吗？
You didn't see the guy outside?
是谁
Who is he?
你说呢？
Who do you think?
其实今晚我是跟他在一起
I'm with him tonight.
你不明白？我现在跟他在一起
Don't you understand? I'm with him now.
你说什么？
What do you mean?
他现在是我男朋友，你已经…
He's my boyfriend. You're...
你再说多一次
Say it again.
我现在要跟你分手
I'm breaking up with you!
过来
Come here!
你说什么  过来
- What?
- Come here!
真的？
Really?
我像开玩笑吗？
Don't I look serious?
你小声点行不行？
Not so loud!
你怎么了？
What's with you?
没事吧
You okay?
几时的事？
How long ago?
很久了
Long time!
你也挺厉害的
You're something!
说变就变
Changing like that.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
刚才在餐厅还那么不开心
You were so unhappy!
然后又好像若无其事
And now you look fine.
你说他是不是假装不开心？
Was he pretending to be sad?
这也可以假装吗？
How could you pretend?
像不像？
Was that good?
真的走运，变心那个不是他
Lucky I was the one who changed.
是我
Not he!
变心那个是你？
You're the one who changed?
谁先说，就是谁
Whoever says so first.
如果是他先说
If he said it first,
不开心的就变成是我了
I'll be the sad one.
真的好彩数
Now I should celebrate.
那么，你没有不开心吗？
So you're not unhappy?
没有
No!
我也不知为什么
I don't know why.
不过真的没有
But I'm not.
你可不可以再说一次？
Can you say that again?
我听得不太明白
I don't understand.
我不是说了吗？
I just told you.
那再说一次，做得出哪怕认
Tell me again. You owe me that!
我做过什么？
What did I do?
你自己说呢？
What do you think?
你们上过床没有？
Did you sleep with her?
你说什么？
What are you saying?
上过了？
You did?!
Clara
Clara!
我真不知道，原来你们那么熟
I didn't know you're that close.
上次她生日，你好像是第二次见她
You met her only once
before her birthday.
我不见你两个星期，你就变心
It's only 2 weeks, and you...
不是你想的那么简单
It's not as simple as that.
有多复杂？才两个星期
How complex can it get in 2 weeks?
你说分手就可以，我说分手就要挨骂
You're the one who wanted to break-up.
我说说而已，谁叫你做？
I didn't mean it literally!
我们去完这派对分手吧
We'll break up after this party.
什么去完派对分手？
What do you mean?
我是说去完这个派对就分手
Go to the party, then break up.
去完派对后分手，OK？
Party first, then break up! Okay?
那现在是去派对还是分手？
Which one are we doing now?
分手不可以去派对吗？
Both!
我说我不想去你朋友的生日会
You want to break-up,
你就说分手
I didn't want to go to the party?
是的
Right!
那分手还去什么生日会？
So why should I go
since we're breaking up anyway.
不行吗？
Why not?
我跟我朋友说过你会去
I told my friends you'd go,
那就去了再说吧
so go.
你就是这样
It's just like you.
一走了之，永远是这样
Running away like that.
像一尊佛
What a bore!
你今年多大？
How old are you?
你做事有没有想过后果？
Will you care about
other people's feeling?
想怎样就怎样？
Always having your way.
我就是想得太清楚
In fact, I care too much
about the others!
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas!
Jeannie呢？
Where's Jeannie?
去洗手间
Washroom!
果然你也来了
So you did come.
你干什么？又想骗钱？
Up to your tricks again?
我给你算…你真是…
I'll tell your fortune.
我给你算命，不收钱
At no charge.
不用了，算也没用
No, no need, it wouldn't help.
你好，生日快乐  你好
- Happy Birthday!
- Hello!
谢谢
Thank you!
你们见过面了？
You've met?
是我介绍你们两个认识的
I introduced you two.
你怎可以跟他在一起？
How can you be together?
你们会有报应的
You'll be cursed!
我叫你送她回家
I told you to take her home.
你送她到哪儿去了？
Where did you take her?
真没用，哭得隐形眼镜都掉了
I cried my contact lenses out.
我想你也算是个经典人物
You're something of a classic.
我一不开心就吃雪糕
I eat ice cream when I'm sad.
你没我那样不开心，你吃盒小的
You're not as sad, so eat the small pack.
可知道刚才我为何找你充当男朋友？
I told him you're my boyfriend.
刚才在计程车里我把头靠在你肩上
Because in the mirror in the taxi.
看上去也像情侣，可以瞒得过人
We look good as a couple.
就是这样了
That's why.
很多东西都是骗人的
Not everything is so clear-cut.
好像我现在这样
Like this.
一时看你不清楚，一时又很清楚
You look blurred, now you're clear.
清楚，不清楚
Clear, blurred.
听说有一种东西叫有框眼镜吧
You can wear glasses.
我戴眼镜的样子很难看
I look terrible in glasses.
谁见过我戴眼镜，就一定要娶我
Whoever sees me in them must marry me.
也好，戴给你看看是否真的难看
I'll show you how terrible I look.
但我短期内没准备结婚
But I'm not planning to get married.
怎样？
Well?
请问你找谁？
And you are?
你可以不用吗？
Shut up!
你不见我们要分手吗？
Can't you see we're breaking up?
我告诉你，你一定会后悔
You'll regret this.
你跟她不配，她只是个小女孩
She's only a child.
或者我就是喜欢她这样
Maybe I like that.
我想我在她面前不会像一尊佛
I'm not a bore to her.
那怎么办？
What do we do?
能怎么办？
This is it!
在想什么？
What are you thinking?
你又在想什么？
有否计算过我和你一起的机会率有多少？
What are the chances we'd be together?
说来听听，哪有人这样计算的
Can you tell?
不信我？好，你听著
Listen!
首先那天晚上要不是Clara叫你送我回家
If Clara didn't tell you to take me home.
Clara叫我送你回家
Clara wants me to take you home.
在计程车里想到找你充当我男朋友
And we don't look good as a couple.
就不可能发生
This wouldn't have happened.
更巧的是那晚若不是
Ironic.
Clara揭穿Johnny
If Clara hadn't exposed Johnny.
我见过Johnny跟一个洋妞在一起
I saw Johnny with a Caucasian woman.
你又不是之前跟她分了手
And if you hadn't just broken up.
去完派对后分手
Party first, then break up!
那她就不会叫你送我回家了
Then she wouldn't have told you
to take me home.
你送Jeannie回家吧
Take Jeannie home.
你没有送我回家
If you didn't take me home.
在计程车的倒后镜里根本就看不到你
And I didn't see us in the mirror.
看不到你,我又怎会带你去见Johnny呢？
I wouldn't have brought you to Johnny.
没见过Johnny，我又怎会哭？
And I wouldn't have cried.
怎会分手？怎会发生那么多事呢？
And all these would not have happened.
所以我觉得一切都是注定的
So, it's all fate!
供应商那边的价箍得很紧
The supplier won't give us a break.
我们最多只能赚到三个百分点
We can only gain 3% revenue.
那岂不是白做？
That's not worth it.
不知纽约总公司会否批准，赚那么少
I wonder if New York will allow this.
不如我们再跟供应商谈谈
Let's talk to the supplier again.
我们还有没有第二个供应商？
Do we have another supplier?
有就一早找了
If we did we'd be with them.
Alan，你有什么看法？
Alan, what do you think?
我？
Me?
我觉得无论怎样…
I feel, no matter what.
应该先吃宵夜
We should order supper.
Alan最近怎么了？
What's with Alan lately?
拍拖吧
Dating!
今晚真的不见面？
We can't meet tonight?
你明早还要开会
You have a meeting in the morning.
我无所谓，只怕你辛苦，你知道你…
I'm just worried about you.
我不想你“残”
You'll be wasted.
我还可以
I'm fine.
我知你可以，聊聊天就算了吧
I know, let's just talk.
今晚真的不见面？
We really can't meet?
都三点了
It's 3 a.m.
那么早吗？
That early?
见到面都天亮了
Lt'll be dawn when we meet.
天亮就天亮
Big deal.
你的病还没好，看了医生又不吃药
You're still sick
and won't take medicine.
总是不听话
You never listen to me.
你猜我现在在做什么？
Guess what I'm doing now?
做什么？
What?
秘密
It's a secret.
听不听到我说话？
Can you hear me?
你傻的
You've lost your mind!
你听不听到我说话？
Can you hear me?
疯子
Crazy!
老兄，你没开车头灯
Buddy, turn on your headlights.
真的不见面？
We're really not meeting?
傻瓜
Don't be silly!
你可不要后悔
Just don't regret this.
今晚真是精彩
What an exciting night!
是…
Yes...
近西区隧道对开，西隧对开
Across from the Western Tunnel.
明天有什么事做？
What's up for tomorrow?
待命等电话，又要飞了
Standing by for a call, Flying again.
飞去哪里？
Where to?
法兰克福…
Frankfurt!
德国
Germany!
不飞那么远行不行？
Another long haul?
你明天也没时间
You don't have time tomorrow anyway.
今晚有
But I do tonight.
四点多了，见到面都天亮了
It's past 4. It's almost dawn.
而且你又坏车
And your car.
坏车就坏车
So what.
你来了也没法睡了
You won't be able to sleep here.
没法睡就没法睡
So what!
我来送早餐的
Breakfast delivery.
你真是个疯子
You're nuts!
原来你鼻子好大
Your nose is so big.
比眼睛还大，都不合比例
It's out of proportion.
你的比例也够怪的
Your standard is so strange!
脸也不合比例，正方形的
With your square face.
正方形也可以不合比例的吗？
Why is a square face out of proportion?
我怎么开始时会觉得你英俊呢
Why did I think you're handsome?
你双眉毛也难看吧，粗得可撑船呢
Your eyebrows are so thick.
下颚又阔，像河豚鱼
Cheeks big like blowfish.
嘴也没性格，又不厚又不薄
Mouth beyond description.
那耳朵呢？
And my ears?
不过不失吧
They're average.
我也有点后悔
I regret this.
你闭上眼会不会记得我模样？
Can you see my face
with your eyes closed?
我就记得
I can!
闭上眼又见到你
I close my eyes and see you.
你说我们是不是很熟？
Do we know each other well?
你还有些什么是我不知道的？
What don't I know about you?
我看似是个那么肤浅的人吗？
Am I so shallow?
你觉得，清楚了一个人
Can you still love someone,
还会那么喜欢他吗？
if you know him inside out?
好，你考一考我
Test me!
考什么？
On what?
考一下你有什么我知道后我会不喜欢你
What will make me dislike you.
你这个游戏好像有点矛盾
That's a strange game.
快点
Hurry!
问吧
Ask!
但为什么我要这样做呢？
Why am I doing this?
快点
Hurry!
我有蛀牙
I have a bad tooth.
我知道，早就知道了
I knew that already.
你知你的嘴多臭
Your breath stinks.
我有肝炎
I have hepatitis.
真的？
Really?
你看你
Look at you.
有没有复发过？
Did it become chronic?
我不玩了
I'm not playing.
算了
Never mind.
不过你要补打针
But you need liver shots.
糟，我自己要不要检查一下呢
Should I get tested, too?
你背这袋子的样子好傻
You look silly with that bag.
干嘛给我弄这样一个袋子？跟你交换
Why did you give it to me?
不要，你的袋子那么重
No. Yours is heavy.
不要，它比较衬你
No, it suits you better.
好吧，跟你换了
All right, we'll swap.
你猜我放什么东西在你的袋里
Guess what I put into your bag.
（避孕套）草莓味道的
(Condom) Strawberry flavor.
我们班机什么时候起飞？
What time is our flight?
你好烦，问了又问，十一点十分
I keep telling you, 11:10!
为什么急着走？明天去不行吗
Why can't we wait and go tomorrow?
我想你难得放假，夜机可省一天时间
A night flight
saves a day on our vacation.
为什么放假一定要去旅行？
Why must we travel on vacations?
不可以在家睡觉？
Why can't we sleep at home?
为什么放假一定要在家睡觉？
Why must we sleep at home,
不可去旅行？
and not travel?
你很闷
You're boring!
你刚认识我可不是这样说的
But you didn't say that
when we first met.
像尊佛一样
You're like a statue of Buddha.
抱紧点
Bear hug!
你怎么会在这里？
What are you doing here?
没有…刚从电梯出来
Just came out of the lift.
你去哪里？  去上海
- Where are you going?
- Shanghai!
最近在搞什么？
What are you up to?
还是老样子
Same old things.
怎样？有没有搬家？
Did you move?
没有，还在那里
No, I'm still there.
工作呢？有没有转？
Did you change jobs?
还是那份
Same job!
你的朋友？
Your friend?
是的
Yes!
上个月，我以为见到你
I thought I saw you last month.
是吗？在哪里？
Really? Where?
在哪里？  我帮你拿袋子
- Where?
- Let me take your bag.
在我家里楼下的公园
In the park near my home.
我见到一个女孩很像你
The girl looked just like you.
是吗？
Really?
是
Yes!
我就坐在那里
So I sat there.
坐了一个下午，就等她转过头来
All day, waiting for her
to turn her head.
我心想，你还不看过来？
Thinking, "turn around".
后来怎样？
And then?
不是你
It wasn't you.
怎样？过不过瘾…
Well? Isn't that something?
过瘾吧
That's really something.
你以前的同事蛮有趣
Your friend is interesting.
他很过瘾吧
He's really something.
他告诉我，以前在英国开垃圾车的
He drove a garbage truck in England.
那倒适合他
That suits him.
你说话要这么刻薄的吗？
Do you have to be so mean?
看情况吧
That depends.
他是我朋友
He's my friend.
不过你“朋友”刚才好像盯著你的胸
He was looking at your breasts.
我只是不想你吃亏了还不知道
I just wanted you to know.
他是我很要好的朋友
He is a very good friend.
在我最不开心时他开导过我
He helped me when I was down.
这我也相信
I believe that.
我问你，他有没有追求过你？
So, did he court you?
有
Yes!
还上过一次床
And we went to bed once.
你说这个是来气我？
You told me that to upset me?
我那时候刚失恋
I had just ended a relationship then.
失恋不是一个理由
That's not a reason.
那时候我很不开心
I was feeling very down.
这也不是一个理由
That's not a reason either.
是意外
It was an accident.
女孩是不应该有意外的
Girls should not have accidents.
那你又怎样？以前没试过吗？
And you? You've never done it?
我那时未成年，什么都不懂，不算的
I was younger, then it didn't count.
你这个就叫理由？
And that's a reason?
我是男人，你是女人
I'm a man, you're a woman.
你的理由也很牵强吧
That's a lousy reason.
如果你公平点，你就不会觉得牵强
If you were fair you wouldn't think so.
这样也叫公平？
That's fair?
我们不是事事都要求男女平等的
Men and women are not always equal.
是你自己刚刚说公平的
You're the one who said "fair".
跟你辩论真辛苦
It's hard to reason with you.
你永远跟不上
You never follow other's arguments.
男与女在这方面永远都不会平等
Men and women will never be equal
when it comes to sex.
若你公平点对我
Try to be objective,
你就会同意我刚才说的
and you'll agree with me.
不知你在说什么
I don't know what you mean.
这种人也能骗你上床
Of course not.
你当然不知我说什么
If a guy like that could get you in bed.
我们是不是应该和解呢？
Should we make peace?
我只是不想浪费这张机票
Let's not waste the air ticket.
都是那个垃圾司机惹的祸
It's the garbage driver's fault.
你从来没提过他
You never mentioned him.
那就证明他不重要
That means he's not important.
不重要，但上过床
No, but you slept with him.
没有一个男人
No man can accept,
知道自己女朋友跟这种人上过床会没事的
his girlfriend having slept
with a guy like that.
那应该跟谁？
Then what kind of guy is okay?
这个？
This?
也不行
You wish!
那个呢？
That?
那个你也要？
You want that?
那个呢？
That?
不会吧？
You're kidding!
不行吗？
Why not?
那件外套很有问题吧
Look at his jacket.
那个呢？
That?
那个十足像个强奸犯
Looks like a rapist.
这个行了吧？
How's this one?
这个你会吃不消
You'll have a hard time.
你好坏
You're bad!
你看你们男人多烦
You men are trouble.
所以我比较喜欢女人
That's why I like women.
怎样？
Well?
你刚才不应该这样发脾气
You shouldn't have done that.
对不起了
Sorry!
无论发生什么事，虽然你是女人
Even though you're a woman.
都不可以在公众场合做这种事
You shouldn't do this in public.
跟你一起，很多事都是第一次
When I'm with you,
there are a lot of firsts.
例如呢？
Such as?
例如放假要去旅行
Travelling on vacation.
还有…
And...
还有什么？
And what?
还有被人这样“打”
And being hit like that.
我刚才已经道歉了
I said sorry.
我知道
I know.
过来吧
Come here.
这样才对
That's more like it.
赶得要命
Finally made it.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
没什么
Nothing!
那走吧
Let's go!
舞会几时开始？
When does the ball start.
八时
At 8!
有什么人去？
Who will be there?
所有人
Everyone.
大老板，外国合伙人，还有一些大客
Bosses, overseas partner, clients.
我的裙子漂亮吗？
Do you like my dress?
不合适？
Not okay?
你有没有第二条？
Do you have another?
你不觉得好像演马戏吗？
I feel like I'm at a circus.
这样行不行？
How's this?
这样呢？好点吗？
This? Better?
好像夜总会小姐
I fell like I'm at a night club.
这件行不行？
How's this?
行了，不用说
Say no more.
中间那颗玩意儿能拔掉吗？
Can you remove that thing in the middle?
这条好
This is good.
不会太普通吗？
Not to plain?
普通好…
Plain is good.
那走吧
Let's go!
等等
Wait!
什么？
What?
不是吧？
You're kidding.
你自己去好了
Go without me.
这件呢？
How's this?
扎起头发配这条裙子会好看的
Looks okay if I put my hair up.
你扎起头发不太好，腮会很大
Don't, you jaws are too big.
那这个呢？
How's this?
你穿短裙，不好看的
You don't look good in short skirts.
你小腿很粗
Your legs are too fat.
你的同房会有吗？
Does your roommate have anything?
你针对我
You're picking on me!
近来不是嫌我这样，就是嫌我那样
You always find fault with me.
说我的脸像橄榄核，全都不用换了
My face is like an olive,
I shouldn't change.
换掉女朋友就行了
You can just change a girlfriend.
以前我穿什么都好看
I was perfect,
现在却说我小腿粗
now my legs are too fat.
粗你的屁？
Too fat?!
这样穿好不好？
How's this?
好吧
Good!
你喜欢的这条裙子不是我的
It's not my dress.
无所谓的
It doesn't matter.
但我有所谓，你究竟喜欢我什么呢？
It does. What do you like about me?
如果我不是现在这个样子
If I didn't look like this.
你开始时会不会和我在一起？
Would you have gone out with me?
你不是这个样子就不是你了
But then you'd be someone else,
对不对？
right?
是的，都是我
Yes, it's all me.
如果你不是现在这个样子
If you didn't look like this,
我同样会喜欢你
I'd still love you.
不奇怪
That's not hard.
就算你什么都没有，我也会喜欢你
Even if you had nothing, I'd love you.
别再这样说我
Don't treat me like this again.
你们分手也好多年了，拜托
You guys have broken up long ago.
我现在也没说要跟他在一起
I didn't say I wanted to be with him.
见见面都不行吗？
Can't we see each other?
你每次见他都那么倒霉
Everytime you see him
you bring bad luck.
换了是我，也不想见你
Even I wouldn't want to see you.
是的…
Yes...
来吧，别那么伤心  你耍我
- Come, don't be so sad.
- You making fun of me?
你这么伤心，就不要吃了
Don't eat it if it makes you sad.
你耍什么花样？
What are you trying to do?
你越是痴缠，只会越惹他讨厌
The closer you get the more he hates you.
在忙吗？
Are you busy?
是的
Yes!
还要忙多久？
How much longer?
还要忙一阵
A while!
为什么不说话？
Say something.
没什么
It's nothing.
他完全不当我一回事
He ignores me.
我试过装作不紧张他
I pretended I didn't care.
他还是那样对我
But he's just as mean.
你怎样装作不紧张他？
How did you pretend?
我试过整个星期说话时不看他
For a week I talk to him
without looking at him.
难度也挺高的
That's very difficult.
是的，很高
Yes, very.
我很想见你
I want to see you.
不行，还没忙完呢
No, I'm still busy.
不如我上来吧
Why don't I come to your office?
上来做什么？
And do what?
看你工作
Watch you work.
上来看我工作？
Come here to watch me work?
你到哪儿去了？
Where are you now?
我坐对头车来
I'll take the other train.
那班车刚开了
That train just took off.
我还是不上来了
I'm not coming.
免得你说我麻烦
So I won't be in your way.
你爱不爱我？
Do you love me?
在忙
I'm working.
那我回去了
Then I'll go home.
我们结婚吧
Let's get married.
好吧，几时？
Sure, when?
明天
Tomorrow.
那你跟我秘书约个时间吧
Make an appointment with my secretary.
不如真的结婚吧
Let's really get married.
你想不想我？
Do you miss me?
想
Yes!
有多想？
How much?
是不是厌了？
Are you tired of me?
不是
No!
我知道你是
I know you are.
以前一晚做三次
We use to do it 3 times a night.
现在这样会没命的
Now we'll die before that happens.
你说你行的
You said you could.
现在不行了
Not any more.
我很想见你，你想不想见我？
I want to see you. Want to see me?
想的
Yes!
真的想？
Really?
我现在就上来
I'm coming over.
我还是回家了
I'm going home.
还要忙多久？
How much longer will you be?
还要忙一阵子
A while!
别做得太晚
Don't work too late.
再见
Goodbye!
我来送早餐的
Breakfast delivery.
还没走？
You're not done yet?
还没有？
Not yet?
那明天给我电话吧
Call me tomorrow.
睡了，再见
I'm going to bed, bye.
你们不是九时关门吗？
Aren't you open till 9?
今晚收早，什么事？
We close early tonight.
我有一部手提电脑要取回
I have a notebook I have to pick up.
可不可以开门让我去拿
Can you open up to let me get it.
但我不知是哪一部
I don't know which one is yours.
你们有个同事帮我修理的，麻烦你
One of your guys is fixing it for me.
他今晚提早下班了
He left early.
你开门让我自己去拿吧
Let me get it myself.
他今天下午打电话来说已修理好了
He called to tell me it's done.
我都不知道是哪一部
I don't know which one it is.
我知道，我有单据，麻烦你
I do. Here's my receipt. Please.
但我没钥匙
I don't have the key.
有钥匙的人已走了，你明天再来吧
That guy is gone. Come back tomorrow.
我们走吧
Let's go.
你能不能帮我叫他回来？
Can you get him back?
我都没有他的电话
I don't have his number.
你明天再来吧，我们十一时开门
We open at 11. Come back then.
我男朋友今晚要飞了
My boyfriend's flying tonight.
所有档案都在电脑里，很重要的
All his files are inside. It's important.
不是黑色那本，奶奶
Not the black one, Grandma.
是红色小小的那本
The little red one.
这本不是红色吗？这本就是红色
Isn't this red? It's the red one.
你的字那么小，谁能看得到？
Your handwriting is too small.
你听我说
Listen to me!
第一页
On the first page.
揭开第一页那面
Open it to the first page.
写在上面小小斜斜的字，奶奶
The small numbers on the side.
你读给我听
Read them to me.
九六四
964.
你等等…
Wait a moment.
你说，九什么？
9 what?
九六四…九六四
964... 964...
一个九六四还是两个九六四？
Was that one or two 964's?
九六四…九六四…零七七七
964... 964... 0777
奶奶，你听著
Listen, Grandma.
我问你是一个九六四还是两个九六四
Was that one or two 964's?
零七七七…九六四…零七七七
0777... 964... 0777
奶奶，我问你是一个九六四
Grandma,
还是两个九六四？
one or two 964's?
臭小子，现在不就读给你听吗
Brat! I'm telling you now.
你们年青人个个都是这样
All you young people are the same.
一天到晚都不在家
Never at home.
想开热水炉都没人帮我开
No one to turn on
the water heater for me.
炉头又没开，洗澡也没得洗
I can't even take a bath.
连饭都煮不了，惨过住老人院
Or cook, it's worse than a nursing home.
臭小子
You brat!
是的，回来开开门吧
Yes, come back and open up.
她说她男朋友今晚要飞
She says her boyfriend
is leaving tonight.
是的
Yes!
真是麻烦
What a drag!
是，你回来开吧
Yes, come back.
好，麻烦你
Thank you!
他正赶来
He's coming!
Alan
Alan!
你不是要飞吗？
Aren't you leaving tonight?
是的，改了
It's been changed.
修好了？
It's fixed?
是的，还以为你急着用
I thought you needed it soon.
我刚才一直在开会
I've been in a meeting.
都忘了告诉你
Forgot to tell you.
你们要出去？
Are you going out?
刚开完会很累
It was a long meeting.
现在打算到外面吃东西
We're gonna go grab a bite.
你呢？
And you?
等会儿去哪里？
Where are you going?
那回家吧
Then go home!
行了
Fine!
怎么了？
What is it?
没事
Nothing!
你这样还说没事？
This is nothing?
是的，我又发疯了，行吗？
Yes, I'm going nuts, okay?
你等我一下
Wait for me!
我和你去吃点东西吧
We'll go eat!
不去，不用你可怜
No! I don't need you your pity!
那你回家吧
Go home then.
褟家俊，有种你别再找我
Alan Hing, don't ever call me again.
我很忙，很辛苦
I'm busy. This is difficult.
你别整天发这种脾气行不行？
Can you stoop these daily tantrums?
那分手吧
Let's break up!
你分个够
Go ahead!
褟家俊
Alan Hing!
我也有事要忙
I work, too!
不只你一人有同事有会开有饭吃的
You're not the only one with meetings.
那就好了
That's great.
为何你永远都不懂欣赏我替你做的事
Why don't you appreciate what I do?
我没叫你做那么多事
I didn't tell you to do all this.
为什么要做那么多事？
Why must you do everything?
这个我会买的，不用你为我买
I can buy these myself.
电脑我可以叫秘书去取
I can ask my secretary to pick this up.
叫助手去也行
Or get a messenger.
你为什么总要为我做那么多事
Why are you doing all this for me?
因为我疼你
Because I care about you.
疼一个人不是这样的
That's not caring.
我真的不明白
I don't understand.
我也不明白
Neither do I!
我好辛苦
This is hard for me.
我也辛苦
And also for me.
分手，好吗？
Let's break up, okay?
究竟我做错什么？
Where did I do wrong?
那是我错吧
It's my fault!
是不是我越对你好，你就越嚣张？
The better I treat you,
the worse you become.
你以前不是这样的
You were different.
你以前也不是这样的
So were you.
因为我对你越来越好
Because I treated you better.
一吵架总是男人错
In a fight it's always the guy's fault.
为什么要弄得这样不开心？
Why are we so unhappy?
我想我们不是太了解
We don't understand each other.
我原来不清楚你
I don't know you well.
但我很清楚你
But I know you well.
那你比我幸运
Lucky you.
我以前觉得你…
I thought you were...
很过瘾，很有性格
Something. Had personality.
这么说，我现在没性格了？
So now I have no personality.
现在你只会紧张我
You only care about me now.
紧张你有什么不对？
What's wrong with that?
是你不稀罕
You take me for granted.
如果有人这样对我，我一定很开心
I'd be happy if someone cared.
是不是我不紧张，你就满意？
You'd be happy if I stopped caring?
其实不止这样，还有其他…
It's not only that.
不过算了
But forget it.
分手吧，我不想勉强你
Let's just break up.
我也不知道，不知道自己想怎样
I don't know what I want.
我知道
I know!
你想分手
You want to break up.
其实我想了很久，我也不想…
Actually I've thought of it
a while now... but...
行了
Enough said.
再说很老套
It's getting ugly.
我不想你不开心
I don't want you to be sad.
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
你放心，我不会再烦你
Don't worry, I won't bother you again.
请问，Edmond在吗？
Is Edmond there?
你打错电话
Wrong number!
打错？不可能的
That's impossible.
请问你是不是90978820？
Is this 9097-8820?
是的，不过没有你要找的人
Yes, but there's nobody here
by that name.
又没有我要找的人？
Nobody?
不可能的，明明是这个号码
That's impossible. It's this number.
这样…是不是你记错了
Did you remember the wrong number?
你用了以前朋友的电话，你不知道？
Or are you using your friend's old phone?
我想你搞错了
You're mistaken.
又搞错？不可能的
Again? Lmpossible.
明明是这个电话号码，这样…
It's this number.
你真的没记错？
You remembered right?
真的没用你朋友的电话？
You're not using your friend's phone?
没有
No!
这样…不好意思，打扰了
Well, sorry to trouble you.
这样就…再见
Well, goodbye.
再见
Goodbye!
怎样？听够没有？
Well? Heard enough?
看电影吧
Let's catch a movie.
这两个，谢谢
These two, please.
还是不看了
Never mind.
喝些东西吧？
Get you a drink?
麻烦你来两杯红萝卜加雪梨
Two carrot and pear juices.
没有雪梨
We're out of pears.
没有雪梨，那要…
You are, then...
那么多橙，两杯橙加什么好呢
Two glasses of orange and what else?
买东西？
Shopping?
你认为我是否应该去找他？
Do you think I should look for him?
昨晚电话响了没人听
Last night the phone rang.
我想是他打来的
I think he was calling.
我上次叫他别再找我，可能…
I told him never to bother me,
but maybe...
那你就问他有没有打电话找你
Call him and ask if it was him.
你也认为我应该打电话给他？
You think I should call him.
那次他也说不知道自己的决定对不对
He wasn't sure
he made the right decision.
整整一个月了，小姐
It's been a month.
要后悔早就后悔了
He's had plenty of time to show remorse.
你说我现在去找他，他会怎样
What will he do if I look for him?
他只会令你更难受
Make you feel worse.
你怎样？
You okay?
为什么他要令我更难受？
Why will he make me feel worse?
因为他不再喜欢你了
Because he doesn't love you anymore.
别哭了
Don't cry!
为什么？
Why not?
其实你喜欢他什么？
What do you like about him?
他真的那么好？
Was he really that good?
你再找第二个吧
Find someone else.
上次Johnny还不是这样？
It was the same with Johnny.
怎么人家不喜欢你
You feel worthless,
你就觉得自己全没用？
if they stop loving you.
许多人还很喜欢你的
Many people love you.
干嘛要这样，看你把自己弄得…
Don't, you're making yourself...
多难看
So ugly!
可多陪我一会儿吗？
Stay with me!
要不要我再陪你一会儿？
Want me to stay longer?
等会儿你上公司来，今晚我没事做
Come to my office. I'm not busy.
我陪你
I'll keep you company.
保重
Take care!
再见
Bye!
先生，请问要些什么？
What can I get you, sir?
咖啡
Coffee!
你瘦了
You've lost weight.
你等会儿还要回去？
You have to go back?
其实我这次来…
I come to...
咖啡，先生
Your coffee, sir!
其实我这次约你，是想跟你说
I asked you here to tell you.
我觉得我们可以再做朋友
We can be friends again.
上次找你，你的同事说你去了伦敦
I called. They said you were in London.
是吗？你找过我？
You called me?
是的，我去受训一个月
I went for a month of training.
上个星期才回来
Came back last week.
升职了？
A promotion?
可以这样说
You can say that.
但还要看面试的表现
But it depends on the interview.
除了我，还有五个同事
There are 5 other candidates.
升什么职位？
For what post?
事务长
Purser.
机会大不大？
A good chance?
还可以，虽然六个选两个
It's okay. They want 2 out of 6.
但我和另一个同事资历比较深
But another person and I are more senior.
那就好了
Good!
其实你应该重视你的事业
You should work on your career.
这两个多月来发生了很多事
A lot has happened in these 2 months.
不只是你，还有其他很多很多事
Not only you, but many things.
我觉得自己像被人催眠了一段时间
I feel I've been hypnotized.
“啪”一声，突然醒来
Then "bang", awakened.
其实我真的很不成熟
I'm really immature.
每次见到以前的男朋友
Everytime I see an ex-boyfriend.
我都觉得很奇怪
I feel strange.
我觉得我不可能喜欢过他们
I feel I couldn't have loved them.
原来我也不知道自己在做什么
I didn't know what I was doing.
然后就以为这个对我不起
I say he's not good,
那个对我不好
he's not nice.
其实问题是我自己
But the problem is myself.
跟你分开后，有段时间我很恨你
After we brokeup,
I hated you for a while.
恨你恨得入骨
Very much so.
我甚至觉得，我对你那么好
I felt, I was so good to you.
你有什么理由不要我？
You have no reason to dislike me.
我这么喜欢你，你没理由这样对我
I loved you, and you mistreated me.
所以我可能说了一些我不应该说的话
So I said things I shouldn't have said.
只是因为…我要你一样不开心
Because I wanted to hurt you.
而原因是因为你伤害了我
Because you hurt me.
但想不到，原来根本都不关任何人事
But it's really not one else's business.
一切，皆因我自己不够成熟
It's all because I'm not mature enough.
之后就是英国…
When I went to England.
我下飞机的第一步就想哭
I wanted to cry as soon as I landed.
因为我记得你说过
Because you told me.
如果以后你真的拍拖
When you have a girlfriend.
你一定会带女朋友去见你以前的教授
You'd take her to see your old professor.
然后你问，我们什么时候过去
Then you asked when we can go.
现在我到了
Now I'm there.
不过，只剩下我一个人
But I'm alone.
我在火车站下车
I got off the train.
望过去你的大学时
When I passed by your university.
我突然觉得你很遥远，我很怕
I felt you were so far away
and I'm scared.
为什么你会变得那么陌生？
Why have you become a stranger?
如果连这感觉都没有
If I didn't have this feeling.
我就什么都没有了
Then I'd have nothing left.
到了第三天，我再去你的学校
On the third day I went to your school.
我坐在你宿舍的饭堂里
Sat in your dining hall.
我想像，你曾经在这里出现过
And thought, you were here.
然后我就哭了，是不是我不够好？
And I cried. Was I not good enough?
我乘火车去伦敦的时候
On the train to London.
碰到一个从香港来的男孩
I met a boy from Hong Kong.
他问我是不是来旅行
He asked if I was a tourist.
我说是
I said yes.
他问，怎么不见你有相机？
He asked where my camera was.
于是他给我拍了一张照片
And took a picture of me.
说回到香港会寄给我
He told me he'll send it back.
昨天我收到这张照片
And I got it yesterday.
他在后面写著“给我哀伤的朋友”
He wrote "To my sad friend" on it.
然后电话响了
Then the phone rang.
我突然觉得那电话是你打来的
I had a hunch it must be you.
于是我拿起电话
So I picked up.
但没有声音，不久就挂断了
But there was no sound.
我觉得，一切都应该完结了
I feel everything must come to an end.
突然间，我所有感觉都跑回来
Suddenly, all my feelings returned.
就好像在四年前
Like 4 years ago.
我刚刚毕业，搬出来住的时候
When I graduated and moved out.
所有东西，都是刚刚开始
Everything was new.
突然间，我的心不再痛了
My heart stopped hurting.
我不再不开心
I was no longer sad.
心又好像跑回来一样
As thought my heart has returned.
我觉得我可以重头再来了
I can start over.
我曾经想过找你
I thought of looking for you.
写过很多信给你
Wrote letters to you.
但都没有寄出
Didn't mail any.
因为我跟自己说，如果我找你
I told myself, if I look for you.
而还存希望想你要回我的话
And hope that you still want me.
我就一定不容许自己那样做
I wouldn't do it.
因为我不可让人再这样对我
I won't let anyone
treat me like that again.
我跟Heman说，我想找你告诉你
I told Heman
I wanted to find and tell you.
我已经不再紧张你
I no longer care for you.
她说，如果不紧张，根本就不用找
He said if that is so
I wouldn't need to find you.
我说我不想让你觉得,我没有你就不行
I said I didn't want you
to think I need you.
Heman说，算了，Jeannie…
Heman said, forget it, Jeannie...
你斗不过，斗不过的
You can't win.
我知道，所以我不再斗了
So I give up.
我只可以说
I can only say.
我真的很喜欢…很喜欢你
I really loved you.
然后很伤心…
Then I was hurt.
然后…
Then...
我希望有一天，我不再伤心
I hoped one day the hurt would stop.
可以重新来过
And I can start over.
我一直在等这一天
I've been waiting.
希望快点来
For that day.
而这一天终于来了
And it's finally here.
来了？
Is that you?
这里我搬动过
I've moved these.
你的东西我收拾过了
And packed up your things.
怎么了？你又玩车？
You had another car accident?
哪有，开工从那里摔下来的
I fell down at work.
你的东西在那边，看看齐不齐
Make sure your things are all there.
你真行，一年的东西平时不拿
You left everything here for a year.
要拿就一次过全拿走
And now you're taking it all at once.
本想用车载去给你的
I wanted to bring some to you.
这本书我的？
Is this book mine?
是的
Yes!
我几时有本这么闷的书？
When did I get such a boring book?
那时我叫你看的，你就看了
I wanted you to read it so you did.
你今日生日
It's your birthday today.
是的
Yes!
不过没有礼物
I don't have a gift.
没想过今天会见到你
Didn't think I would see you today.
我公司调我去别的地方
I've been transferred to another base.
是吗？去哪里？
Really? Where to?
夏威夷
Hawaii!
Alan，你真的不去吗？
Alan, you really are not going?
不去了，你们玩得开心点
No, you guys have fun.
再见
Bye!
你是不是认真的？
Are you serious?
问你拿一年大假是认真吗？
You really want to apply 1 year's leave?
认真点，你是不是要跳槽？
Are you looking for a new job?
跳槽记得约我一起
Tell me when you look for a new job.
如果不会游泳
If I can't swim.
应该可以先学潜水吧
Can I start with snorkeling?
可以吧
I guess so.
你调走了，男朋友怎么办？
What about your boyfriend.
他要陪我过去
He going with me.
拍拖拍成怎样？
How's your girlfriend?
拍什么拖？
What girlfriend?
散了？
You broke up?
跟谁散了？
Brokeup with who?
你不是跟一个洋妞拍拖吗？
Weren't you with a Caucasian woman?
哪个洋妞？
What Caucasian woman?
Clara说见到你跟一个洋妞看午夜场
Clara said she saw you at midnight show.
是否认错人了？
It must have been someone else.
碰巧有个洋妞站在我旁边吧
Maybe a Caucasian woman
happened to be next to me.
我已经没事了，骗你干嘛？
Why would I lie to you?
我不明白你这样紧张干什么？
Why are you so upset?
过了一年你才来问我？
You waited a year to ask me?
但会不会那天你真的认错人？
But could it have been someone else?
你别管我是否认错人
It's doesn't matter.
总之你现在跟Alan开心就行了
As long as you're happy with Alan now.
Clara，你等等
Hold the line, Clara.
你在哪里？
Where are you?
我现在赶来了
I'm on my way.
好久没试过这么舒服了
Haven't felt this good in a long time.
怎么以前不懂得的呢？
I never knew how to appreciate this.
我有些话要跟你说
I must tell you something.
我也有
Me too.
你也有？
You, too?
爱你
Love you!
一会儿才跟你谈
We'll talk later.
怎样？
Well?
我想我真的搞错了
I must have made a mistake.
你搞错了什么？
About what?
他走了
He's gone.
我以前也试过这样跟踪我女朋友
I stalked my girlfriend like that.
我都不是在跟踪他
I'm not stalking him.
那你在做什么？
What are you doing then?
我也不知道自己在做什么
I don't know.
以前你也是这样跟踪你女朋友
You used to stalk your girlfriend?
是的
Yes!
怎么跟？
How?
从她踏出她家门口那一刻开始跟
From the moment she leaves her home.
一直跟…跟到她回到家为止
All the way until she returns home.
最后结果呢？
And then?
最后病倒了
Then I got sick.
开始以为病好了可以继续跟
I thought I'd continue
after I got better.
但没想到病好了之后又觉得
But when I recover, I felt.
她并不是那么好
She's not that great.
很傻吧？
Stupid, huh?
是这样的了
That's life.
不过我绝对不会有下次
But there won't be a next time for me.
我也是这样说
Me neither!